AKI GAO

xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a JavaScript developer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular Blockchain and the Web. I offer two years of experience in full stack web application development from conception through design, architecture and delivery of elegant and maintainable solutions. My personal mission is to use technology and entreprenership to create a more compassionate and humancentric future by empowering people to connect more meaningfully and reducing socioeconomic inequality. My experiences and expertise range from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly web-based UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures. Specifically, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node is ecosystems.

Education

Skills

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

• Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering

August 2016

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7/ES8), Solidity, Shell (Bash)

UX/UI and Front End Technologies and Tools:

• Sketch, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, React, React Router, Reach Router, Redux, Redux-Saga, CSS Modules, PostCSS

Blockchain Technologies:

• Ethereum, Web3, Truffle, Ganache, Remix, Geth

Development and Testing Tools:

Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Git, Webpack, Babel, NPM, Yarn, Mocha,
Chai

Back End and Database Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, Helmet, Mongoose, MongoDB, MySQL

Infrastructure and Infrastructure Technologies:

Apache, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Travis, Terraform, Packer, AWS,
Azure, Google Cloud

Work Experience

Freelance Consulting - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

February 2018 - Present

- Provide services to clients to architect and develop front end and back end applications, as well as smart contracts.
- Also offer work to clients seeking development capabilities for planned or existing projects.
- Special focus in a JavaScript-based stack including the React and Node.js ecosystem for the front end and back end respectively, as well as Solidity for smart contract development.

Alluminate - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

October 2017 - February 2018

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed, developed and maintained the Alluminate homepage and the CryptoPets landing page.
- Core development member of the CryptoPets platform, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets developed in partnership with Arcade Distillery.
- Smart contracts written in Solidity implement ERC721 to tokenize in-game pet ownership.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for correctness.
- Developed in-house development and testing environment using Web3, Docker and Geth.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application July 2017 August 2017
 - Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure.
 - Application built with a Javascript stack (React/Redux and Node.js) and deployed to Azure Cloud.
 - Smart contracts written in Solidity with Truffle and deployed to Microsoft's Blockchain network.
 - Architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project.
 - Led development efforts across the stack, including the UX/UI design, front end, back end and devops, in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
 - Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
 - Participation, expertise and leadership in project led to converting the project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a bid for a contract
- FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment September 2017 November 2017
 - Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment Project.
 - Front end logic built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form, and user interface styled with custom CSS4 using CSS modules and PostCSS.
 - Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI, implementing application logic, and providing high level guidance to other developers.